Hey everybody, it's
Speaker 2: Michael Tracy here, 4th of July, 2025. Congratulations for making it this far. We
don't know how far
Speaker 2: we'll make it from here, so savor every moment. We
are in Staten
Speaker 2: Island, or on Staten Island, or at Staten Island. The precise article to use in that context is up for eternal debate.
Speaker 2: But let's not get bogged down in that for now.
We did some
Speaker 2: interviews today at the 4th of July parade, which we're told is the longest continuous 4th of July parade in the United States since 1909, is that right? Or 1911? 1909, 1911. Again, still some debate over the precise origins, but either way...
I'd say was a
Speaker 2: slice of Americana Megan the cameraman was nodding an agreement and what I wanted to do was as calmly and genially as possible ask
people in
Speaker 2: this part of Staten
Island
And what
Speaker 2: they thought of Trump bombing Iran, I think it's fair to say that there was an over-representation of Trump supporters demographically in this area, some of whom were actually wearing Trump paraphernalia, so they were easy to spot. But it was also, just generically speaking, a place you would definitely associate with Trump support in Staten Island. And
I hope
Speaker 2: people don't accuse me of...
Speaker 2: cherry-picking or asking leading questions but as you'll see every single one of them that I asked who wanted to address the
subject
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): was strongly supportive of Trump bombing Iran correct camera
woman
Speaker 2: she's nodding so what is my extrapolation from
that I don't know that I
Speaker 2: want to make the entire argument in full comprehensive
detail right
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): now but I will note
that
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): That in the lead up to Trump bombing Iran, there was a lot of online discussion about how MAGA was supposedly divided or
in a
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): civil war over the wisdom of bombing Iran. And all along, my impression was that this narrative was being greatly exaggerated. And...
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): The result of an over-interpretation of some like outlier media personalities and podcasters and so forth Whereas if you actually look at the hard data poll after poll has shown Overwhelming supermajority support among Republicans, which you can think would be the MAGA base, right or even if you select for Republicans with a strong preference for Trump or even self-identified MAGA Republicans the
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): level of support for bombing Iran goes up even higher so This
Speaker 2: whole narrative was a little bit contrived confabulated I think and That Contention of mine was further bolstered I would say by these sort of Man-on-the-street type interviews that we did today on the 4th of July where we celebrated our independence as a nation by asking people about Trump bombing Iran so enjoy
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): so
uh
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): Since foreign policy has become somewhat unexpectedly a big feature of this mayoral
Speaker 5: race, what was your view on the U.S. and Trump bombing Iran recently? Did you support that?
Speaker 6: Totally in favor of that. Obviously, the Ayatollahs and his supporters, every day on a Friday, they'd come out of their mosque, their day of prayer, Juma. They would scream, death to the big Satan, death to the little Satan, meaning United States and Israel. So they had every chance in the world
to
Speaker 6: create a peaceful environment they chose not to. So I agree with the president launching that attack on their nuclear capabilities. Do you
think
Speaker 7: bombing Iran is consistent with the notion of America first? Because
there was some
Speaker 7: controversy among
Speaker 8: at least some segment of Republicans as to whether those were consistent ideas.
Speaker 9: Yeah, no, that's open for discussion. Just like I support the Ukraine versus Russia. There are others in the Republican Party who said, no, we shouldn't be backing the Ukraine. That's what
a democracy is.
Speaker 9: is about fair and open discussion. And then you resolve your differences at the ballot
Speaker 8: box. - Is whether something is consistent with America First resolved by Trump just declaring it
Speaker 10: so, and he's the one who defines it, or is there some other way to resolve that philosophical debate?
Speaker 6: - Well, I think that debate will always take place because the president is the commander in chief. He will make decisions that he feels in the best interest of not just the country,
Speaker 6: but he's the leader of the free
Speaker 9: world so i defer to the president on that and i'm more than happy to have discussions with those who are on my side of the republican line who might disagree with both the bombing of iran and the support for the ukraine
Speaker 11: do you think
Speaker 8: uh... israel has played an outsized role
in
Speaker 8: this campaign for good reason or has it been a little bit excessive like Andrew Cuomo tried to run the Democratic Party against a Democratic primary gets Mamdani largely emphasizing the issue of Israel and it didn't clearly resonate enough for him to prevail in that contest so has
it
Has
Speaker 8: it gotten too much air time or is it actually relevant to New York City such that it should be one of the most prominent issues discussed?
Speaker 6: Well, I think anti-Semitism certainly is a prime time issue. But I think the voters have told us again
Speaker 9: and again, whether they're Democrats, Republicans, independents, that affordable housing, cost of living, quality of life and crime are the big four issues. Clearly, anti-Semitism has to be addressed. And Zoran... Is criticism of
Speaker 8: Israel...
Speaker 8: automatically one in the same with anti-semitism
I
Speaker 9: support the state of Israel obviously there are people who have problems with their government as people in Israel do there are divisions between the religious and the secular that's their business they are a democracy but I support the state of Israel because I've been there three times and I see how they're surrounded by
Speaker 8: well it's our business too if we're gonna be funding them with our taxpayer dollars and sending munitions
Speaker 10: and coordinating intelligence operations for them
Speaker 10: to bomb Iran, etc. So beyond
Speaker 12: just criticism of the government, it's also something that's a policy issue for the United States, right?
Speaker 9: Well, you would have had an opportunity to run a third-party candidate. You had a Green Party candidate, Stein, who believed in that. Last time I looked, he was 1% Stein. So people backed Trump overwhelmingly, who is a friend of Israel and has supported them to the max.
I
Speaker 9: think most Americans back Zelensky in the Ukraine versus Putin.
Speaker 13 (higher-pitched voice): Finally, Eric
Speaker 14: Adams is here at this parade in Staten Island today. People have been begging you to drop out and endorse
Speaker 8: him or join forces with him. Are there any discussions along those lines or anything that you can reveal in terms of what negotiations might be underway?
Speaker 15: Why would I bow out? I just beat him in a poll. He's last in a poll.
He's
Speaker 9: rated at 12.
-
Speaker 14: All the big donors who he's been meeting with recently say that he's the only viable alternative to Mom Donnie.
Speaker 9: - How did that work with Cuomo versus Zohan? All the big money people were with Cuomo. How did that work out? So now, because they've been scorned, they didn't expect a loss, it's like all of a sudden they're on the rebound, so they go to Eric Adams.
That's
Speaker 9: not going to work against Orhan. You've got to get out into the streets. You've got to get Gen Zs and millennials on your side, which I have on my side. Adams doesn't. Cuomo doesn't. So let the campaign take place and let the voters decide by November 4th. But I'm not getting out of this race. And you think I respond to billionaires and millionaires? I represent the
Speaker 6: blue-collar working class. The people in Staten Island are not billionaires and zillionaires.
All
Speaker 6: right.
Speaker 16: Thank you. Happy Fourth of July. Happy
Fourth of July. I'm
Speaker 8: curious, since it's the Fourth of July and we're reflecting on America and so forth, what was your view of Trump bombing Iran a few weeks ago? Were you supportive of that, opposed to it, somewhere in between? I'm supportive of that because
Speaker 17: it makes in strength we can gain more peace and I think we showed.
Speaker 17: the people of the United States how powerful we can be when we take action against terrorism. And if they try it again, I think that Trump will be even stronger. But I think we can maintain peace with that type of system where negotiations have failed over months and months and months. So that's my opinion. And I praise my country on the 250
Speaker 17: anniversary because i'm also an associate marine brooklyn one detachment two seven and i'm also a member of the catholic war veterans as an associate well
thank you
Speaker 18: for your service which uh which uh conflict did you serve in oh no it didn't serve i'm an associate i serve now to do anything the marines want gotcha um so did you vote for trump
Speaker 19: uh yes okay yes
Speaker 8: and
you
Speaker 8: Trump has been strongly supporting Israel. Do you consider that consistent with America first, which is Trump's big slogan, meaning put America first? And yet some people maybe raise questions about whether that comports with also being so profligate in support of
Speaker 18: Israel with...
Speaker 18: military support financial support economic support and and so on
Speaker 21: yes because
Speaker 22: Israel is our closest friend we have someone in the Middle East we can depend on with their type of intelligence they have and such a small country all the rest of their lives have to fight for their freedom so
Speaker 25: I proud that the United States has a great friend with the greatest technology
Speaker 25: and systems that we can work with and
Speaker 18: that we can count on them at all times.
Speaker 5: We're curious, since we're all reflecting on America today, what did you think of Trump bombing
Speaker 8: Iran recently?
This
Speaker 26: is 4th of July, I'm not commenting on that. But I like what he did, I'm ex-military. So you do like what he did? He
Speaker 7: stopped the war,
right? He
Speaker 7: stopped it by bombing Iran?
Speaker 27: Are they messing with Israel anymore?
Is any of
Speaker 27: our troops getting killed anymore? No,
they're not. Well,
Speaker 20: Israel started it, right, by launching a preemptive strike on Iran. No.
Speaker 27: No. No, they didn't. Iran has been bombing us for how many years? Bombing Israel? No, bombing us. And
Speaker 28: Israel. They've been missing all their proxies for how many years? Because of Biden, right? When
Speaker 27: Biden released all their money from them, they went nuts. The
Iranian
Speaker 8: military has been bombing the United States?
Speaker 27: Uh...
Speaker 27: Not them per se, but Hezbollah.
Speaker 26: Remember they were shooting our ships a couple months ago? Oh,
Speaker 5: the Houthis in Yemen?
Speaker 26: Yemen and all that, that's where
Speaker 5: they get all their money
from. Right.
Speaker 5: Okay, so right there. So you basically support what Trump did?
Yeah,
Speaker 26: that's my man.
Speaker 5: You're a voter of Trump?
Speaker 26: That's right.
Speaker 8: Trump's all
the way.
So
Speaker 8: just as a group, since today's a day to sort of reflect on America,
Speaker 5: just curious what you all thought of Trump bombing Iran recently. Was it good, bad? I don't
Speaker 29: know. I love Trump,
so.
Speaker 30: We're Trump supporters.
Speaker 31: We're Trump
Speaker 30: supporters. You are? Yes. So what did you think about
Speaker 32: him bombing Iran recently? I believe he had good reason.
Speaker 33: You do? Yes. What was your reason?
I
Speaker 34: just believe in him. And whatever he does, I'm all for. So if in
Speaker 31: the abstract, maybe you might be a little wary of something, if he says it's necessary, you
Speaker 5: defer
Speaker 35: to his judgment because you're a longtime supporter of him.
Speaker 36: Yes. Yes. Yes.
Speaker 35: That's it. Let's
just hope he
Speaker 37 (higher-pitched voice): does his job and he does it well. That's
all we
Speaker 37 (higher-pitched voice): can hope.
Speaker 37 (higher-pitched voice): We're counting on him.
Speaker 38: What did you think of the whole Iran episode?
Speaker 37 (higher-pitched voice): I, I, I... Can we get paid for this interview? No, I'm sorry. No, listen. Um, what, like I said, whatever he thinks, if it's gonna work, let's do it. Right. And hopefully, it will bring us some peace.
Speaker 8: Hey, how you doing? What's up? Is this your setup here? Yes.
Speaker 5: That's amazing. Thank you. What's your name? Steve. I'm Mike. This is, uh, Megan. We're
just doing some video reports
Speaker 5: on the parade for, uh, Rumble.
Speaker 5: Just curious, since it's the 4th of July, we're reflecting on America. What did you think of Trump bombing Iran recently? Did you support that? It
Speaker 41: should have been done 30
Speaker 42: years ago. Oh, really? Why is that? Why? Because of everything Iran's done. Everything Iran's done to Israel. Like what? Like terrorist actions and Hamas and, you know, all the reporting I've seen on it, you know.
Do you
Speaker 8: think it's the role of the United States to bomb Iran's nuclear facilities if Israel wants that to be done? Yeah,
I don't want to
Speaker 43: answer any more questions. I'm sorry.
Speaker 5: Okay. Have a good day. So, what's your name? Joseph Mutoli. And do you live around here? Right
Speaker 44: here. I'm sorry.
Speaker 5: So, since it's the 4th of July, we're reflecting on America and so forth. I'm curious what you thought of Trump bombing Iran recently. Did you support
Speaker 46: that? I
Speaker 47: supported it. You know why? You
Speaker 48: don't know what that country's going to do. And now they didn't know retaliation. They knew it, you know.
Speaker 48: - This man, he don't fool
Speaker 49: around, you know, he's crazier than the rest of them. No, seriously, and they fear him,
Speaker 50: which we need in this
country.
Speaker 14: - Do you think that it could result in a broader war, potentially? - No. They already said that
Speaker 51: there's no retaliation with that, so... -
But
Speaker 14: once you start bombing, you never know what could happen in a month, six months. - What if they started bombing? They got
Speaker 49: the nuclear attacks,
too.
The
Speaker 49: first person that's going to get hit is New York.
Speaker 20: You think Iran would attack New York with a nuclear bomb?
Speaker 49: Oh, definitely, definitely. They hate the United States, definitely.
Speaker 13 (higher-pitched voice): But there was some controversy or dispute over whether they had actually acquired a nuclear weapon,
Speaker 52: because that's been claimed by Israel and others for a very long time, and it hadn't come to fruition, but now, supposedly, it was different.
Speaker 50: It's your say, my say.
we
Speaker 50: get in an argument or a thing you did this I say well he did this in an accident we really
Speaker 49: don't know the truth but it is good to have a supporter behind us that'll stand up for the country whether he's right or wrong it's still like you know God forbid we do get bombed 9/11 we got hammered that wasn't
Speaker 47: Iran though no but it was their
neighbors
- Well that
Speaker 47: was, yeah, we get it down. -
Speaker 50: The people there I feel sorry for. - A lot of people got killed. - Just like you and I. Then it's the government that they weigh on the people. People don't want this, they wanna be our friends. We wanna be their friends.
Speaker 53: I think
Speaker 54: war is terrible. I was in six years, I know war is-- - Where did you serve? - United States Army Reserves.
Speaker 55: I was in the United States for six years,
yeah.
War is a
Speaker 56: terrible thing.
Speaker 14: What do you think about the idea of regime change? Trump suggested it while the Israeli bombing campaign is underway, but as of yet there hasn't been a full Iraq-style invasion or anything, but what about regime change in principle? Do you think that the U.S. should be involved in facilitating regime change in Iran? Between Iran and Israel. I mean, you want to be- Israel is very closely tied to the U.S., though. Thank
you.
-
Speaker 49: But that should be between the two countries. We should be like in the back as a mediator. Russia should be also as a mediator. You know, this way you got balance.
- Well, one
Speaker 20: last question, just curious, in terms of Russia, since you mentioned it, Trump said
Speaker 35: yesterday that
he was
very
Speaker 35: disappointed with Putin. He's not happy about how his negotiations have been going because Putin doesn't seem interested in ending the war. What do you think the status of that conflict is and Trump's role as a mediator? The two of them are like
Speaker 57: Abbott and Costello.
Speaker 55: Except less funny. And I support Trump. But the two of them, they know each other. They
play games.
Speaker 49: - Do Trump
Speaker 59: and Putin are like
Speaker 49: Abbott and Costello? - Yes, and they play games. - With nuclear weapons. - Thank you, and they know this, so that, you know, I don't, the both of them should be in the background.
- And you got
Speaker 52: your Trump hat on and so forth. Just curious, what did you think about Trump
Speaker 20: bombing Iran recently? Did you support that or not?
Speaker 60: - Of course. They can't be a nuclear power. They're terrorists, absolutely.
Speaker 61: I mean,
they should,
Speaker 61: We have to make sure that we keep Not only us, especially America All they want to do is kill death to America And Israel But we have to keep the
Speaker 62: world safe That's our job We're the superpower So
do you think it
Speaker 63: should be the
Speaker 64: job of the United States Essentially to determine which countries Get to become nuclear powers or
not?
I
Speaker 65: mean, listen, we control a lot of the way the world is, right? We fund a lot of countries,
Speaker 66: we help them. Absolutely, it's in our best interest. If it's in our best interest, I think Trump did an amazing job. He kept us at will out of it as much as possible. Israel had to do what they had to do. He kept us as safe as he could because he didn't want us to be totally involved and have...
He
Speaker 66: didn't want to have troops on the ground. He did what he had to do and it came to a point, if they wouldn't negotiate, they wouldn't kill their nuclear plans, he had to take it out. I think absolutely it's our
Speaker 67: job to make sure that we're safe. Everything that he does is within our best interests.
Speaker 8: So this was the first time
Speaker 35: in history that there was an active joint bombing campaign between the United States and Israel, which does
Speaker 68: amount to a very significant escalation in the U.S.-Israel relationship. Is that something that you think is a good idea?
Speaker 62: The two biggest military forces in the world being allies? Yes, I think that's a good idea. Absolutely. Yeah, I don't think there's anything wrong with that. And we both seem to have the same kind of thought as far as democracy and what government should be. So absolutely, I think it's a good thing to be allies with them. Do
you
Speaker 8: think it's consistent with the idea of America first, which Trump talks about to be so profusely supportive of Israel or aligned with Israel, sending them a lot of...
Speaker 8: - Munitions and so forth that are subsidized by American taxpayers?
Speaker 61: - Absolutely, we're not stupid. We're doing what's in our best interest. Just like what
Speaker 62: Afghanistan years ago when they were going after the Russians and we were supplying them. We're doing what's in our best interest. So yes, if Israel's gonna actually do all the dirty work and they're gonna take some of these people out, I have
no
Speaker 61: problem with us supporting
them.
So one
Speaker 5: more question. So regime change, Trump sort of floated the idea of regime change while the Israeli bombing campaign was going on. And some people wonder whether that mean there would be an overt attempt by the U.S. to impose regime change. Do you think the U.S. should be in the business of...
Speaker 5: imposing regime change on
Speaker 31: Iran, or is that a bridge too far?
Speaker 66: - I don't think that's what it was, because Trump said right out that he didn't really want regime change because, like they say, right? You know what you have with the current regime. You don't know what you're gonna get. It could be much worse. So, I mean, 'cause
Speaker 62: I know that Yahoo wanted to take out the regime, but Trump was like, "I don't think it's a good idea."
Speaker 35: - Well, he did threaten to potentially assassinate the Ayatollah.
Speaker 69: - Correct.
Speaker 35: Who, Trump? - Trump did, Trump
Speaker 69: did. - Well,
Speaker 69: I mean, I don't remember. Posted
Speaker 70: it on Truth Social. Anyway, it doesn't matter. But
Speaker 66: yeah, I mean, if
it comes
Speaker 66: to it, then yes. But I think more we wanted the Iranians
Speaker 62: and their own people to kind of stand up and maybe take out the regime. I mean, they're the ones who have to...
Speaker 62: They have a terrorist terrorist government that's running there running their country. They're the ones who should do it So I mean, I don't think we would take them out unless it actually posed a huge threat to us But if so be it if that's what it comes down to if if our Safety is it at stake
Speaker 71: then so be it. So happy 4th of July. Thank you Are you from around here Satin Island?
Speaker 72: Natives that my husband and I are natives. Yes.
Speaker 11: Excellent so
We've
Speaker 11: been talking to people at this parade today and
Speaker 2: since the 4th of July is an occasion to reflect on America and so forth, we're curious
Speaker 10: what people think of Trump's decision to bomb Iran recently, so you obviously have the Trump hat, were you
Speaker 73: supportive of that, what were your
Speaker 72: thoughts in general?
I
Speaker 72: know for a fact that the
Speaker 74 (higher-pitched voice): the mandate was that Israel was the small Satan and
Speaker 72: the United States was the the big Satan and it was only a matter of time with a madman at the helm.
Speaker 72: I thought it was, we would have,
I
Speaker 75: thought we would, what did I, didn't I say I ran? Yeah, I thought, in context. I
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): just thought it was a matter of time before this madman who has nothing to lose at 86 years old, he
Speaker 74 (higher-pitched voice): might have done something drastic. It would have made 9-11 look like a bonfire. Meaning
like he would have
Speaker 77: attacked the United States?
Speaker 74 (higher-pitched voice): Absolutely, absolutely. In
Speaker 77: what fashion? First
Speaker 74 (higher-pitched voice): Israel, then the United States, with the nuclear bomb. Okay.
I
Speaker 74 (higher-pitched voice): don't think it was wise to let him
Speaker 72: have it, he's unpredictable, he's full of hate, and he had a vendetta, and, you know, it takes a Republican to stop a war, end a war, it takes a Republican, and that's what we have in the White House now, and he's putting out so many fires that he inherited.
Speaker 72: with such obstructionism in his wake that we need, we MAGA people, we supporters
Speaker 74 (higher-pitched voice): have to vote Republicans in. It's a matter of life and
Speaker 10: death. Well, he didn't inherit a war with Iran. That began under his term.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): Well, let me just tell you what my understanding is. Okay, we didn't inherit a war
Speaker 72: with Iran.
Speaker 72: during Trump's first administration, he crippled them financially.
Speaker 79: Obama got in and sent pallets full of cash,
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): billions of dollars to Iran, and they refurbished, and they were able
to
Speaker 72: send armaments and have all these satellites, Houthis and Hezbollah, and he supported all these hateful countries.
Speaker 72: So, that's what Obama, that's what Democrats
do.
Speaker 2: Well, Obama
Speaker 80: had a diplomatic
Speaker 2: arrangement with
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Iran. So there was something called the JCPOA or Iran deal that Trump later withdrew from. But the idea of that diplomatic
Speaker 10: arrangement was to limit Iran's ability to enrich uranium with international
Speaker 11: inspection.
And
Speaker 11: then that would address IAEA, yes, inspection. But Trump then withdrew from that. And Trump was at least
Speaker 10: ostensibly trying to negotiate for two months with Iran before the bombing started. Yes,
to
Speaker 81: get rid of the nuclear
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): armaments, to let our people in. He tried everything. Going in, sending our...
our
Speaker 74 (higher-pitched voice): stealths there. He tried everything to avoid it. He did not want that. 60 days, right? He gave them 60 days. But
the
Speaker 77: U.S. demanded no enrichment whatsoever, so Iran would have to totally dismantle its nuclear
Speaker 10: facilities, essentially. And Iran has been adamant for decades, well before Trump, that as a matter of national pride, they would insist on retaining
Speaker 10: their enrichment capacity so it was kind of like an ultimatum that trump and whitkoff his envoy sort of imposed on iran and then that eventually led up to a bombing campaign which might have been avoided if there were different conditions associated with the you know
Woman 82: who said when somebody says death to israel death to america believe them
Woman 82: That's what he said.
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): No, it's a heinous situation, and you could never trust. I mean, everyone has stated you can't trust Khomeini, whatever. What's Khomeini? Khomeini. Khomeini, yeah. You can't trust him, and he
was never
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): going to let other inspectors in,
Speaker 84: legitimate inspectors.
What
Speaker 11: about the idea of regime change so while the Israeli bombing campaign was underway and Trump was supporting it but before the US entered and directly bombed Iran, or maybe it was just after, sorry I'm messing up the chronology, but Trump did sort of float the idea that maybe it would be nice to potentially bring regime change to Iran or I don't know if you saw it he posted on his social
media.
Speaker 11: basically
Speaker 10: floating the prospect of regime change. Do you think that's something that the U.S. should attempt to
Speaker 8: impose or facilitate within Iran? Or is
that too
Speaker 8: extensive of involvement?
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): - I don't want to make a martyr
of him.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): You know, but I think what
Speaker 85: Israel did, eradicating all his top people, his top military, all his, you know, nuclear... - Scientists.
Speaker 85: and all those people, I think that was brilliant. So that's the way to go. Leave him alone at the top, naked and afraid. And when
Trump
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): always says like, I know where you are.
- Right,
Speaker 77: he sort of intimated that he could assassinate him if he wanted to.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): - Exactly. Meanwhile, they're saying the same
thing about him.
and
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): nobody's picking up on that. They
have
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): a fatwa against our president. And do you think the Democrats care? Do you think they even come out and say, that's a red line? So
is the
Speaker 86: war really over then? I mean, if there's a fatwa against the president, it doesn't have to be resolved one way or another? In
other
Speaker 11: words, do you think
that...
the
Speaker 11: ceasefire that
Speaker 87: we're in now is actually the end of it? Or could there be further military action?
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): - Well, you know, Medneved in Russia has said, we're going to supply them with another atom
bomb.
Speaker 88 (higher-pitched voice): So, you know, and Trump said, and we'll take that out. So it's just gonna be a vicious circle.
-
Speaker 77: Did you see yesterday, Trump was asked about his phone call with Putin and
Speaker 10: he said,
that
Speaker 10: he's very unhappy with Putin and he feels like he's making no progress with Putin in terms of the Ukraine situation. And then after the phone call, Russia launched
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): one of its biggest aerial attacks on Ukraine just within
the past
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): few hours. So what do you think of Trump's role in that conflict? I
Speaker 89: talk politics with really
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): informed people.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): And someone I really give a lot of credit to told me that it's another brilliant move by Trump saying that we're going to pull back our armaments from
Speaker 90: Ukraine.
It's now
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): putting it in Europe's hands. Let them do something. They're the ones that are in harm's way.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): Let them start spending some money on Ukraine. Why does it have to be the United States? So I think it's a brilliant move by
Trump. He
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): may have
Speaker 91: to change directions. He may have to supply more and more.
US weapons are
Speaker 92: still flowing to Ukraine. There was just like a bureaucratic
Speaker 10: pause within the Pentagon to review certain weapons systems. But it's not even clear that that's a long-term pause. We'll have
to see.
Speaker 10: But...
Speaker 10: The U.S. still isn't involved militarily in Ukraine by furnishing weapons.
Speaker 93: Yeah, I read that. It wasn't a complete withdrawal or something.
Woman 82: But I think it's a good twist to put out there
and
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): maybe have people sit up in their chairs and say, well, you know, we're going to have to do something.
You know,
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): I think Trump doesn't do anything by accident. I really think he's had four years to think about...
what
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): he needs to do, and he's doing it brilliantly. I was
with him
Speaker 77: last week at the
Speaker 18: NATO summit in the Netherlands, yes. With the White House press operations, so yeah, that was interesting. As
Speaker 94: Rumble? Rumble and
Speaker 18: Substack, yes. Oh,
Speaker 94: Substack. Oh, oh. Have you heard of it? Of course.
Speaker 95: Okay, cool. I'm informed. I'm impressed. I'm impressed, too. Thank you.
Speaker 11: Explain the history of this particular parade, because this is my first year here, but it's sort of like an institution on
Speaker 96: Staten Island, right, or just give us a little bit of background
Speaker 97: on it. All right.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): This is what I've been told since I've been very young. This is the oldest 4th of July parade in the United States. Oh, really? That's what I'm told. 16
Speaker 98: years. 16
Speaker 99: years? Okay. Yeah. And this was all Polish,
Speaker 100: all Polish.
They
Speaker 100: came from Poland and they came to Travis.
Everyone
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): knew each other. Most of us were related. And my parents, my grandparents, lived at 79 Cannon Avenue. And then my uncle moved next door. Anyway, aunts, uncles, cousins spread out all over
Speaker 85: here. And a lot of the original stores are even here.
So there
Speaker 86: were no Fourth of July parades anywhere in the United States before 1909?
This is
Speaker 101: supposed to be the first formal parade
Speaker 102: that has been continuous, yes, with, you know, the exceptions since then.
Speaker 103: Okay. Okay, you want to talk to him? You
got all, you
Speaker 104: got the best information you're ever going to get, and she parlayed Roy Partey with you.
Speaker 14: Excellent, yes. I can only sympathize with what you have to go through on a regular basis. I love
Speaker 105: it. I love what I hear. I
Speaker 14: love what I see.
Speaker 14: I would advise you to take your political cues from this lady. She's very well informed.
Speaker 106: We're in sync.
Speaker 14: All
Speaker 107: right.
What
Speaker 68: was your name again?
Speaker 108: Colette Curry.
And you
Speaker 109: live in this neighborhood or is it your neighborhood?
Speaker 110: No. My mother's from this neighborhood. No. We are from Sunnyside. Okay.
Speaker 85: Yeah. Are you from Sunnyside? No. I live in New Jersey, actually. Oh. Yeah. So we're between the colleges, Wagner and...
Speaker 85: St. John's, that's no longer there. My
Speaker 112: sister went to Wagner, so I've been there.
Speaker 85: Great school.
Speaker 72: Yeah, so we're on both teams. No, no, don't go
Speaker 113: there. Teams up for what? I'll go there. Okay. All
Speaker 114: right. So
Speaker 101: what about you? We'll be with some mystery. Your side, yeah. My side? You sort of brought out the other side of the...
Speaker 101: I don't
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): really have a... Well, you know, because only in the sense that I like to
Speaker 14: probe and prod anybody, really, I interview in terms of their beliefs.
Speaker 115: You did a good job because you got the right answer. Yeah, I
Speaker 14: try not to be, like, too confrontational or aggressive, but, you know, you want to just sort of interrogate...
why
Speaker 14: people feel the
Speaker 71: way they do yeah exactly exactly believe me i do the same with democrats plenty
exactly i do
Speaker 71: uh we we interview democrats
Speaker 18: and republicans with the same level of vigor at least i try
Speaker 116: to right megan can
Speaker 71: attest yes yes yes yes am i happy with our interview or just in general
okay
Speaker 117: both um i'm happy with the interview
Speaker 117: Yes. I'm
Speaker 71: trying to be in a festive mood for the holiday. So I guess in that sense, I'm happy. What are you happy? I
feel
Speaker 118: so victorious. I really do. I
Speaker 71: guess Trump passed the big, beautiful bill. On every
level
Speaker 90: with him, on every level. I'm so proud of him. You
know, there
Speaker 11: are a
lot of
Speaker 11: people who are. It's interesting because, you know, I we do a lot of online media. Sorry if we're taking too much of your time,
by the way.
Speaker 11: Okay. We do a lot of online media and there were people on the right who are Trump supporters who were actually upset when he bombed Iran because they thought that it was a violation of his campaign pledge to stay out of wars.
Speaker 119: 29, 30, 36. Trump, his daughter, everything. Bring Trumps in. Life is life. Let's go. Make America great again, baby. Donald fucking Trump. I'm sorry. There you
Speaker 120: go. There you go.
Speaker 71: Anyway, just to wrap up, there were some people in the online media who consider themselves on the right or pro-Trump
Speaker 2: who were upset when he bombed Iran because they felt that it was a violation of his campaign pledge to stay out of wars, stay out of the Middle East, etc. They don't necessarily
Speaker 121: think that supporting Israel so aggressively is consistent with America first.
It's
Speaker 10: sort of a minority view within the coalition of Trump supporters not really reflected here based on my interviews But that was a sentiment one heard. So what do you think about that?
Speaker 122 (higher-pitched voice): Alright? My thinking is that?
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): Don't you think that the White House the Pentagon the CIA? FBI don't you think they might have some inside information making it a Necessity to intervene
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): How do you know that they don't know something is imminent?
Speaker 92: Well, shouldn't they present it to the public if they've got it?
Oh really? Oh
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): really? It's a
Speaker 92: matter of war and peace, like don't we...
We
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): have enough people who are revealing things
and
Speaker 124: sabotaging him. No, no, I don't think for a minute that they can open it
up. So
Speaker 10: you think the government, when it wants to make a case for going to war, they don't have an obligation
to
Speaker 10: reveal the evidence that they're going on to the public so the public can make an independent evaluation like when if Biden if the same logic applied to something Biden wanted to do would you be okay with him concealing that information
Woman 82: well do you think it was a secret when he said they cannot have a bomb no that was
Speaker 92: very consistent about
but it's not
Speaker 92: even clear whether they had one like that's what that's
what the
Speaker 92: dispute is
And
Speaker 92: Israeli intelligence asserted
Speaker 10: that they were very close to having one, but there's evidence that that has contradicted even the American intelligence assessment. So it's unclear. I
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): know. The American intelligence. You
see
Speaker 10: Tulsi Gabbard,
Speaker 11: the DNI. She testified with very different information not too long ago, and then the Israeli intelligence contradicted it. So
Speaker 71: there's a dispute. So my preference would be for that to be aired in the public and show the evidence, and then we can make our own independent evaluation. - And
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): who's going to be the deciding?
I
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): mean, if the president says we're going to bomb, do you think that they
Speaker 125: have a rally
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): and
Speaker 122 (higher-pitched voice): saying, no, we Americans don't want you. We want you to just stand down. Do you think that's the way to go?
I think the public should
Speaker 122 (higher-pitched voice): be as informed
Speaker 10: as possible about what the government's doing, especially in terms of.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): military action and whether we get embroiled in an overseas war. Do
you
Speaker 124: know what happened in 9-11? Yeah. Clinton, no, not Clinton. Okay.
Speaker 72: Bush was president, but they had these sorties
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): coming in and taking flying lessons, and they didn't want to learn how to land. You know that, right? I'm sure you know that. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): And we had...
Speaker 126: That had nothing to do with Iran.
Speaker 72: No, I said Saudi, right? It was a Saudi Arabia. Yes, you did. I said Saudi. You said the Saudis. Yeah, the Saudis. So, they had a very prominent... Flight
Speaker 127: schools and things in Florida, California.
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): And there was a very prominent person in security, in national security, who brought this to the attention
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): of the
Speaker 128: most important people in the cabinet.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): Richard Clarke.
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): No, somebody else. Tall, dark, and handsome. You know who that was? Do you know? I can't remember his name. Dark and handsome? Yeah. He was the one that said...
There was a
Speaker 14: counterterrorism advisor named Richard Clark who was warning about al-Qaeda
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): relatively early on in Bush's first term and then became like a little bit of a whistleblower. He wrote a book about how his pleas were
Speaker 10: ignored and so forth. I don't know if that's who you're referring to. He wasn't tall, particularly tall, dark, and handsome, so maybe I'm missing something.
Speaker 122 (higher-pitched voice): And there was a woman, Jamie...
-
Speaker 122 (higher-pitched voice): Another female-- - Oh, I know what
Woman 82: you're
Speaker 129: talking about, Jamie Gorelick.
Woman 82: - Gorelick, he told Jamie--
Speaker 129: - She was on the 9/11 commission.
Woman 82: - Right, he told her-- - We're going deep now. - This is what, okay, I'll wrap it up. - No, it's fine, yeah. - But, yeah, she said, you know, he went to her. Anyway, then you gotta do something about this. There's something wrong, they shouldn't be here
Speaker 131: learning just to fly and not land. So
Speaker 132: anyway-- - And how does that relate to
Speaker 88 (higher-pitched voice): the Iran situation? - Okay, all right, okay. Do you know what happened to that man who went to Jamie
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): Gorelick?
He
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): worked out of 9/11 he worked out of the World Trade Center. Do you know he perished on 9/11 that same man?
Do
Speaker 7: something Equivalent to attacking the World Trade Center.
Speaker 88 (higher-pitched voice): No the thing is when you don't pay attention to intelligence
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): when you just don't go deep when when you let people obstruct you and when you know the right thing to do and You don't do
it
you're
Speaker 78 (higher-pitched voice): just as guilty and that's what i mean 9 11 didn't have to happen if people just
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): paid attention to the threats
if they
Speaker 76 (higher-pitched voice): just paid attention to the harm that can be done to the american public well trump said you know don't touch an american don't
Speaker 134: don't kill one american or you'll hear from us you won't you know you'll you'll pay the price that's a good thing
right all
Speaker 13 (higher-pitched voice): right got it i i i i i i i see what you're trying to say yes i see what you're saying yes